ATHM Textile Industry Stereographs 6524/006 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series I: Images of Mills, Alphabetical by Location
  - Massachusetts, Ware (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Item 3: Otis Co., Ware, Mass. (Box 4, Folder 25)
      ca. 1870. Written on reverse in ink, Trim shop and finishing room. Exterior view with river in foreground. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - Massachusetts, Williamsburg (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Item 1: H. L. James Woolen Factory, Williamsburg, Mass., 1874 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      May 16, 1874. No. 5 in the series, "Views of Hampshire Flood!" Photographed by F. J. Moore. View of men standing amid the rubble. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: Williamsburg Cotton Mills, Williamsburg, Mass. (Box 4, Folder 26)
      n.d. Uprooted trees and the mill beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - Massachusetts, Worcester (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Item 1: Flood at Hunt's Mill, Cherry Valley, Worcester, Mass., 1876 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      March 30, 1876. No. 7 in the series, "The Flood at Worcester, Mass.""Views of the Flood at Worcester, Mass." Photographed and published by J. W. & J. S. Moulton, Salem, Mass. View of men standing near ruined mill and water wheel. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 2: Flood at Ashworth & Jones Mill, Worcester, Mass., 1876 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      March 30, 1876. No. 14 in the series "Views of the Flood at Worcester, Mass." Photographed by Lawrence. View of the water wheel and damaged mill building. 17.5 x 10 cm.
  - Missouri (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Item 1: King Cotton, St. Louis Mo., 1904 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Mississippi Exhibit, Agriculture Building, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, St. Louis, Mo. H.C. White Co. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Claremont (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Item 1: Monadnock Mills, Claremont, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 1)
      n.d. Photographed by J. T. Locke. View of ruined mill building along river, chimney in background. 17.5 x 11.5 cm.
    - Item 2: Monadnock Mills, Claremont, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      n.d. No. 99 in the series, "New England Views, Stereoscopic Views" photographed and published by G. E. Stevens. Bird's eye view of mills. 17.5 x 10 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Dover (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Item 1: Cocheco Mfg. Co., Dover, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      n.d. View of the river and mill.17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 2: Cocheco Mfg. Co., Dover, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      n.d. View of mill building, Biddle's Bazaar, horse drawn City Omnibus and driver. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 3: Washington St. and Mill, Dover, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      n.d. Written on reverse in ink, Washington St. business part. Photographed by F. H. Foss. View of Businesses along Washington St., Cocheco Manufacturing Co. in distance. 17.5 x 8.5 cm
    - Item 4: Cocheco Mfg. Co., Dover New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      n.d. published by O. H. Copeland, Newmarket, New Hampshire. Written on reverse in pencil, Part of Central St. Dover. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 5: Sawyer Woolen Mill, Dover, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      n.d. Stamped on reverse: Fred H. Ross. Horse and wagons outside the mills. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 6: View from Mayo's Hill, Dover, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 2)
      ca. 1900. View of two ladies and a child picnicking on a hillside, with river and mills in background. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Franklin (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Item 1: Franklin Mill, Franklin, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      ca. 1865. Written on reverse in ink, Taken about 1865, Franklin Woolen Mill. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: [Franklin Mills, Franklin, New Hampshire] (Box 5, Folder 3)
      F.J. Moulton's Photograph Gallery, Tilton, and Franklin, New Hampshire Written in pencil on reverse: "View from [word crossed out] School House Grounds." View from hill showing buildings that may or may not be part of mill complex; larger mill building in left background. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 3: Franklin Falls Mill, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      n.d. Photographed by D. W. Herrick. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: Franklin Mills, Franklin, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      n.d. Woman standing on porch, mills beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 5: Mills, Franklin, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      n.d. Written on reverse in pencil, Franklin Mills, Franklin, New Hampshire, Salmon Falls Mfg. Co., Salmon Falls, NH. [?] View of trees and river and mills beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Great Falls (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Item 1: Great Falls Manufacturing Co. Old No. 1 Mill, Great Falls, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      ca. 1878. Photographed by F. C. Philpot. Trees and mill buildings. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 2: Great Falls Manufacturing Co., Cloth Hall and No. 2 Mill, Great Falls, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      ca. 1878. Photographed by F. C. Philpot. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 3: Great Falls Manufacturing Co. New Dam Mill, Great Falls, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      ca. 1878. Photographed by F. C. Philpot. Workers standing in front of mill building. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 4: Great Falls Manufacturing Co., Mill at New Dam, Great Falls, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Item 5: Great Falls, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      ca. 1878. Written on reverse in ink, Main Street looking North. Photographed by F. C. Philpot. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 6: Great Falls Manufacturing Co., Great Falls, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      ca. 1878. Photographed by F. C. Philpot. View of canal. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 7: Great Falls Manufacturing Co., Great Falls, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - New Hampshire, Guild (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Item 1: Granite State Mills, Guild, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      n.d. No. 50 in the series, "New Hampshire Scenery." Photographed and published by John Bachelder, Andover New Hampshire. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Harrisville (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Item 1: Reflections in mill pond, Harrisville, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Albumen print, ca. 1870-1885. Image depicts a mill pond in the foreground, in which are reflected several mill buildings and/or houses in the background. No. 20 in a series of stereocards on Harrisville, New Hampshire, published by French & Sawyer, Portrait and Landscape Photographers, Keene, New Hampshire 15.25 x 7.75 cm. (w/out mount); 17.5 x 8.25 cm. (w/mount).
    - Item 2: Cheshire Mills, Harrisville, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Albumen print, ca. 1880. Image depicts the Cheshire Mills in Harrisville, New Hampshire, with employees, both male and female, lined up outside the mill. Mill is four-story granite building with cupola and bell (?) on roof; a three-story building is attached on the right. On reverse: D.S. Rice, Photographer, Harrisville, New Hampshire 16.5 x 8 cm. (w/out mount); 17.75 x 8.75 cm. (w/mount).
    - Item 3: Harris Mill, Harrisville, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 6)
      n.d. Stamp on reverse: D. S. Rice, Photographer. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: Houses in Harrisville, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Albumen print, ca. 1870. Image depicts houses in Harrisville, New Hampshire, with a church (?) on the right (building has steeple). Water (pond or brook) visible in foreground; man standing in center of picture on far side of water. On reverse: D.S. Rice, Photographer, Harrisville, New Hampshire 16.5 x 8 cm. (w/out mount); 17.75 x 8.75 cm. (w/mount).
    - Item 5: "New Mill," Harrisville, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 6)
      Albumen print, ca. 1869-1870. Image depicts the M. Harris Company's building known as the "New Mill" in Harrisville, New Hampshire The building is a four-and-a-half story brick building (with a basement story as well), with a five-story tower in front. Men and women pose in the stair tower on each floor and in front. Similar to image XXIV in FACTORY UNDER THE ELMS with some variations; probably earlier since no tower cap is shown. On reverse: D.S. Rice, Photographer, Harrisville, New Hampshire 16.5 x 8.25 cm. (w/out mount); 17.75 x 8.75 cm. (w/mount).
  - New Hampshire, Keene (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Item 1: Beaver Mills, Humphrey Machine Company, Keene, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 7)
      Image of three-story brick buildings on left and right; smaller building with tall smokestack in center background. Two men barely visible in loading dock window of second floor in building on right. Painted on smokestack: "Beaver 1871 Mills." Horse-drawn carriage in center background. Printed on back "Selected List of Stereoscopic Views in Keene and Vicinity, Published by J.A. French, No. 10, Bridgeman's Block. No. 626. [after 1871]. 17.75 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Laconia (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Item 1: Mill Town, [Laconia, New Hampshire.] (Box 5, Folder 8)
      n.d. Bird's eye view of town with RR tracks in foreground. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Lake Village (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Item 1: Lake Village, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 9)
      n.d. From R.R. [by Colis?] Photographed by E.D. Ward. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: Wing Dam, Lake Village, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 9)
      n.d. Photogrpahed by E. D. Ward. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Manchester (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 1: Amoskeag Mills, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. View from across river. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: Amoskeag Falls and Covered Bridge, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 3: Amoskeag Bridge Interior, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Photographed and published by A. B. Hamor, No. 271 Essex St. Lawrence, Mass. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: Baptist Church, Machester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 5: Amoskeag Dam, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. View of dam under construction. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 6: Down River from Amoskeag Bridge, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 7: Amoskeag Dam and Gatehouse, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 8: Mill Housing, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 9: Langdon Mills, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Photographed and published by A. B. Hamor, No. 271 Essex St., Lawrence, Mass. Exterior view from across canal. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 10: Langdon Mills Overseers Block, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Stamp on reverse: C. K. Burns. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 11: Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Published by A. D. Stark Two women sitting riverside, mills beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 12: Mills, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. No. 454. Photographed and published by Kilburn Bros., Littleton, New Hampshire. View of the river and mills. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 13: Merrimack Square, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      View of park with pond in foreground and buildings in background. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 14: Merrimack Square, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. View of woman standing beside picket fence, pond and buildings beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 15: Merrimack Square, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. View of pond and buildings beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 16: Smyth's Residence, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Photographed and published by A. B. Hamor, No. 271 Essex St., Lawrence, Mass. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 17: Ash Street School House, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. No. 34 in the Manchester Views series. Photographed by M. L. Daggett, published by C. K. Burns. View of students and teachers standing in front of school. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 18: High School, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Photographed and published by A. B. Hamor. Shows students and teachers standing outside of school. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 19: Stark Mills, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. View of mills and surrounding landscape. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 20: Stark Mills, Manchester, New Hampshire. (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. No. 41 in the Manchester Views series. Photographed by M. L. Daggett, published by C. K. Burns. View of R.R. tracks running between mill buildings. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 21: Granite Street & Bridge, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Photographed by A. B. Hamor No. 271 Essex St., Lawrence, Mass. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 22: Elm Street, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. No. 452. Photographed and published by Kilburn Bros., Littleton, New Hampshire. 17.5 x 9 cm.
    - Item 23: Hanover Street, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 24: Hanover Street, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 25: Stark Street, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Photographed by Ellinwood & McClary. Snow scene. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 26: Amoskeag Falls, Fair Grounds & Surroundings, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Item 27: Elm Street, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. View of buildings and horse drawn carriage. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 28: View of City from Rock Raymond, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 10)
      n.d. Photographed and published by A. B. Hamor. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Milford (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Item 1: Pine Valley Carpet Mill, Milford, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 11)
      Before 1874. From the series, Milford and Vicinity. Published by E. Lovejoy, photographed by S. R. Hanaford. Shows a three-story building with a four-story tower in the center. Ahorse-drawn buggy with two men in it is in front of the mill; several employes stand in front of the mill on the edge of the field; other employees are leaning out of the windows and loading docks. By 1874, the Pine Valley Carpet Mill had become known as the Hillsborough Mills. Located in the Pine Valley section of MIlford, close to the Wilton, New Hampshire, town line; the mill is sometimes erroneously placed in Wilton. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Nashua (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Item 1: Jackson Mills, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. Photographed and published by H. P. Moore, Corncord, New Hampshire. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: View from Iron Bridge, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Item 3: Suspension Bridge and Jackson Co. Mills, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. No. 16 in the series, Views of Nashua, New Hampshire Published by E. F. Gopp & Co. View of R.R. tracks, people, and suspension bridge and mills beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: Falls, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. Photographed and published by H. P. Moore, Concord, New Hampshire View of dam and falls, mills beyond. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 5: Chandler Street, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. Photographed by C. A. Lawrence. View of men standing outside buildings on street. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 6: Indian Head Mills, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. Photographed by C. A. Lawrence. Written on reverse in ink, Indian Head Corporation as seen from the from bluff. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 7: Canal Street and Canal, Jackson Co., Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. No. 14 in the series, "Views of Nashua, New Hampshire." Published by M. V. B. Greene. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 8: Mills, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Photographed by C. A. Lawrence. View of housing and mills beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 9: Nashua Corp., Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. Photographed by C. A. Lawrence. Written on reverse in ink, Nashua Corp. Mills and canal from the west. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 10: Upper Corp., Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. No. 19 in the series, "Views of Nashua and Vicinity." Photographed by Stark & Horton. View of logs in river and mills beyond. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 11: Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Negative by H. P. Moore, Concord, New Hampshire ca. 1900. View of mill complex with house in foreground. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 12: Nashua River, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. Photographed and published by H. P. Moore, Concord, New Hampshire. River in winter. 17 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 13: Main Street, South, from Gibby's Drug Store, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. From the series, "Nashua and Vicinity," published by E. Lovejoy, Milford, New Hampshire Photographed by S. R. Hanaford. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 14: Harbor Pond and Mills, Nashua, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 12)
      n.d. No. 18 in the series, "Views of Nashua New Hampshire." Published by E. F. Gopp. View of people pond-side, church and town in distance. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, New Market (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Item 1: Main Street, New Market, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 13)
      n.d. View of storefronts on Main Street. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Penacook (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Item 1: Bird's Eye View, Penacook, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - New Hampshire, Portsmouth (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Item 1: Kearsarge Mill, Portsmouth, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 15)
      n.d. Portsmith and Vicinity, Davis Bros., Portsmouth, New Hampshire 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Rochester (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Item 1: Rochester Woolen Co., Rochester, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 16)
      n.d. Photographed by A. J. Whittemore. View of wood pile and people walking through mill complex. Written on reverse in ink, Front of Nos. 1 & 2 mills, Rochester. 17.5 x 9 cm.
  - New Hampshire, New Hampshire: Suncook (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Item 1: China Mill, Suncook, New Hampshire, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Views, Suncook, New Hampshire Published by J. Wilkins. View of R.R. tracks, mills and dam, town in distance. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: China Mill, Suncook, New Hampshire, 1867 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      Written on front in pencil, China Mill, Suncook, New Hampshire 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Tilton (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Item 1: Winnepissiogee Cotton Mill, Tilton, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Written in pencil on reverse: "Tilton New Hampshire Cotton Mills." F.J. Moulton, Tilton, New Hampshire Photographer. View of mill; water coming over dam just visible on right. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 2: [Winnepissiogee Cotton Mill, Tilton, New Hampshire] (Box 5, Folder 18)
      Written in pencil on reverse, "Cotton Mill Tilton NH Herbert L. Pratt [sp?] Agent 1873." View of mill reflected in the Winnipesaukee River. 1873? 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Hampshire, Troy (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Item 1: Weave Room, Troy Blanket Mill, Troy, New Hampshire (Box 5, Folder 19)
      Interior view showing workers in the weave room of the Troy Blanket Mill, ca. 1880. H. L. Chase, Keene, New Hampshire [photographer]. Sold by H. C. Newton, Troy, New Hampshire The Troy Blanket Mill was famous for its horse blankets. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New Jersey, Patterson (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Item 1: Patterson Mills, Paterson, N.J. (Box 5, Folder 20)
      n.d. Beokel Bros. Exterior, bird's eye view of Mills. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New York, Cohoes (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Item 1: Harmony Mills, Cohoes Falls, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 21)
      Harmony Mills, Cohoes Falls, N.Y. n.d. View of mill on riverbank. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 2: Exterior view of No. 2 Mill, Cohoes, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 21)
      n.d. Cohoes Manufacturing Company? Photographed by J. H. New. View of Mill in winter. 17.5 x 10 cm.
    - Item 3: Exterior view of No. 3 Mill, Cohoes, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 21)
      n.d. Photographed by J. H. New. Exterior view of mill in winter. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
    - Item 4: Exterior view of No. 3 Harmony Mill (Mastodon Mill), Cohoes, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 21)
      n.d. Troy, N.Y., and Vicinity, published by Union View Co., Rochester, N.Y. 17.5 x 11 cm.
    - Item 5: Exterior view of unidentified mill [Ogden Mill?]. Cohoes, N.Y (Box 5, Folder 21)
      ca. 1890. Photographed by J. H. New. Exterior view of mill in winter. Ogden Mill was a hosiery mill; at some point in the 19th century it was purchased by Harmony Mills. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New York, Glenham (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Item 1: Glenham Carpet Works, Glenham, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 22)
      n.d. Written on reverse in ink, Old Glenham Carpet Works from near the dam. Groville, N.Y., present "Texaco". 18 x 10 cm.
  - New York, Little Falls (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Item 1: Mills and Bridge on Mohawk River, Little Falls, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 23)
      n.d. No. 6637 in the series, "Scenery at Little Falls. On the Mohawk, New York." Published by E. & H. T. Anthony & Co., 501 Broadway, N.Y. 17 x 8.5 cm.
  - New York, Utica (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Item 1: Globe Woolen Mills, Utica, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 24)
      View of mill building with trees directly in front. 17.5 x 9 cm.
  - New York, Victory Mills (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Item 1: Saratoga Victory Mfg. Co., Victory Mills, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 25)
      n.d. View of trees and mill beyond. Scratched into image, "Victory, From old Gravel Bed". Photographed by C. H. Pease, Schuylerville, N.Y. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New York, Waterford (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Item 1: Cotton mills of Waterford, N.Y., 1867 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      D. A. Henry, Stereoscopic Views, Brattleboro, Vt. View of mills and city in the valley beyond. Written on front (ink) Waterford, near Troy, from Cohoes. 17.5 x 8.5 cm.
  - New York, Watertown (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Item 1: Eagle Mills, Watertown, N.Y. (Box 5, Folder 27)
      n.d. Exterior view of mills, horse drawn carriages and workers in front. 17.5 x 8.5 cm
  - North Carolina, Greensboro (Box 5, Folder 28)
    A visit to White Oak Cotton Mills, Greensboro, N.C. the largest denim mill in the world. H.C. White Company, [N. Bennington, Vt.]. Gelatin silver print stereocards, c1907, c1909. Consists of 25 stereocards in a "stereo-pack." Includes views of White Oak Cotton Mills (owned by Proximity Manufacturing Company), many different operations in the mill (spoolers, slashers, weaving, etc.), social services provided by the company (cooking and sewing classes, boys' welfare club), recreation (bands, baseball teams), and officers of the company.
    - Item 1: No. 1. White Oak Cotton Mills, Greensboro, N.C., 1909 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      H.C. White Co., N. Bennington, Vt. Gelatin silver print. No. 1 in a set of 25 stereocards. Text on reverse: "This plant, located just North of the City of Greensboro, N.C., is the largest denim mill in the world. It is owned by the Proximity Manufacturing Company, which also operates another large denim plant at Greensboro, known as Proximity Mill. The two plants have an aggregate of 110,000 spindles and 3500 looms, and employ about 2500 operatives. They consume 60,000 bales of cotton annually (30,000,000 lbs.), and have a daily output of over 200,000 yards of denim." The White Oak Cotton Mills made denim. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 2: No. 2. Opening machines, White Oak Cotton Mills, Greensboro, N.C., 1907 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      H.C. White Co., N. Bennington, Vt. Gelatin silver print. No. 2 in a set of 25 stereocards. Text on reverse: "The bales are opened, and the cotton is thrown into the large hoppers at the front of these machines, which open and loosen the fibres, work out lumps and remove the grosser impurities, such as dirt, leaf, seed and trash. A strong air draft carries off the dust and foreign particles, and lifts the cotton through trunks to the floor above. There are twenty-four lines of Opening Machines in the White Oak Mills." The White Oak Cotton Mills made denim. 17.75 x 8.75 cm.
    - Item 3: No. 3. Lapper machines, White Oak Cotton Mills, Greensboro, N.C., 1909 (Box 5, Folder 28)